okay
okay okay folks uh let's get started uh
so uh today I'm going to talk about uh
vision and action so essentially the
problem is how do we use Vision to guide
action and action could mean
manipulation action could mean
navigation so I'm going to start with
this uh study which is uh from like more
than 20 years ago but it's the it's
really cute and really
fundamental but before that let's start
with some high level philosophy so the
high level philosophy is a recap so this
is like my recurring theme which I will
say every few slides so that you don't
forget which is that the way we want to
think about uh
about action and perception is in this
evolutionary setting and the earliest
setting is that of perception for
guiding Locomotion then the next setting
is perception for guiding manipulation
and then finally we have the emergence
of sort of language and and so on so
uh okay so here is the study that I want
to talk about which is
uh it goes back like now it's like 25
years but it was a naturalistic study of
how do we actually use use Vision while
guiding action and it turned out to have
surprising consequences because the most
straightforward things that you think of
of how you use vision is are actually
wrong and
uh because there are few facts about
Vision that are worth knowing one is
that vision is
slow I mean in a way that's the most
fundamental fact about Vision vision is
slow and vision is slow for robots we
always suffer from that when we are
trying to build uh you know manipulation
systems walking systems and so on that
the processing needed for vision takes a
while but this is also true in
biological Vision so if you consider the
various levels of processing starting
from the retina going up to the cortex
it takes like 200
milliseconds 200 milliseconds of delay
for a robotic system is terrible we like
to operate at you know 100 Hertz or
th000 Hertz or whatever when we are
talking about movement of the joints so
the answer is that all the fast stuff in
in action actually happens through the
use of
proprioception and proprioception is
much faster so knowing about joint
angles and so on and communication of
that information to the brain is very
fast so always vision is used in
conjunction with other senses and the
most basic sense that we always have is
proception which is knowing about joint
angles and so
on now how is Vision actually used so
this study by led by Michael land uh is
about what happens when we try to
perform some complex task so what he did
was he tried to to study what happens
when we perform a task like making a cup
of tea so this is a very English study
so the English people when they are you
know in the middle of the day they need
to take a break and go and make a cup of
tea so uh so Professor Lan decided that
he would make that into a research paper
so he developed this technology and this
is uh very cool he this is 1999 by the
way so what you see here is there's a
camera on his head right do you see the
camera on his head it's like some
oldfashioned video camera of some sort
and then on the right panel you see what
is that camera sees so today what do we
call this this is egocentric video right
okay and then and then implicitly what
you see here is that there is another
camera which is looking at the guy doing
whatever he's doing so so that what do
we call that today exocentric video so
this is the first data set which was
collected which was ego EXO okay now
when we when do we have really big ego
data sets uh there's a data set called
ego 4D that I was involved in creating
and that's like two years ago and that
weate collected like 3,000 hours of
video but land was doing this in 1999
right with the technology of the time
furthermore we did a project called ego
4D which you folk should read up on
because it's a great data source and
then we did a project called ego EXO
which was published very recently but
land was already doing this right in
99 okay now uh now the advantage of the
ego and EXO view is that they are
synchronized in time so you need to have
some synchronizing mechanisms which you
can use to try to understand so what he
tried to do was something like
naturalistic where does the eye look at
and uh he was doing uh kind of gaze
tracking now why is gaze tracking useful
because in human Vision the entire
visual field is not observed with the
same resolution we have a phobia so what
we have a central fobia so in a way this
is very nice because this tells us where
we are looking at precisely where we are
fiating that gives us some information
about what's the most what must be the
most important
part
right uh so uh by the way is the
recording going on right now okay I just
wanted to check because I logged out and
logged back in okay so uh so the FIA
tells us where the highest resolution is
po is where the highest resolution is so
where your eyes will will turn to are
the most important parts of it of of the
scene so this is very good okay let's
look at what he does so this is what you
find so uh so let let me give you the
high level picture first okay wait I
think in this uh so these are kind of
the so this gives you a picture of what
are the steps involved in making a cup
of T right so what does he and and this
is what does the I look at so what's
happening in a
so so what he's got is like that time
clock so he basically is looking at the
uh the the kettle right so this is what
he's going to pick up then he's going to
take it to the sink so that's in B then
he's going to essentially fill it with
water right that's what's going on then
he's going to uh you know start switch
it on presumably then there are steps
which involve you know going to the
fridge picking out the milk things like
that okay so so there have lots of steps
and he has listed all those steps going
from a to L by the end of L he's got his
cup of tea so he's happy
okay but look at what the sequences are
the sequences are uh captured in the
slide what's the sequence of
operations there is a whole body
movement towards the object of Interest
so if I'm going to pick up the kettle
and take it to the sink to fill water in
it first thing I need to do is to
approach the kettle so the whole body
turns towards the C that's a whole body
movement Second Step visual fixation of
the object meaning that I look at that
object how do I know that I'm looking at
the object because if I'm tracking my
eyes my gaze is directed at that object
so from the analysis of their two ego
EXO streams I can see that third step
manul relation of the object so in this
case it'll be picking up the
object but here's the cool part when you
are picking up the object you're no
longer looking at the
object the eye jumps ahead so
essentially I look at the object I mean
I turn because I know where to because I
have to actually go pick up the object
so I need to be physically near the
object right I turn towards the object I
look at the object in some ways I issue
the command my brain has issued the
command to go pick up the object and
then when I'm picking up the object my
hand reaches out picks up the object but
at this point the eye is not looking at
the
object this is very very important the
ey is not looking at the object when you
pick up the
object what makes this
possible what makes this possible is
proception because the vision system
locates the object puts it in 3D
space and now we have our our all our
joints and we know the kinematics and
inverse kinematics of the body so we can
the brain can command the right uh you
know sequence of trajectory in joint
angle space so that you can go pick up
the object it doesn't need the eye to
monitor this question
correct so so so Dynamic tasks where the
situation is changing this are slightly
different and I'm going to come to those
later in the lecture because those
impose other constraints but when the
object is static you just you
essentially you you look at the object
you plan what you're going to do and
then you let your you trust your hand to
do the the right thing without needing
to monitor why because you've got
feedback right your proception gives you
an approximate plan and the final steps
can be executed with the help of tactile
sensing on the on the hand you don't
need Vision to take care of it and we
are fortunate that you don't need Vision
to take care of it because vision is so
damn slow it's going to add 200
milliseconds of delay whereas here the
delay doesn't matter because it's just
part of that initial planning step right
and then as the is being executed you
don't need
Vision now what's going on is that this
routine is being followed throughout I
mean this is a very multi-step long
Horizon planning problem to make this
cup of tea but every step what's
happening is that the eye is ahead of
the
hand okay the eye scops out the
situation figures out the 3D location
the identity of the object that is of
interest and then it says to the
motor system okay now you take care of
it and then the eye is off checking the
next step so once you have picked it's
picking up the object and then the eye
is going off looking at the tap because
the tap is next in our journey so you're
the eye is always ahead it's like the
forward Battalion okay and the the hand
is coming catching up on you it's like
one step behind and and and now so so so
think of it as like a pipeline where so
now you're no longer bothered by the
latency right because the latency
doesn't hurt you while you're executing
on the action that is happening very
fast now when does the story fail the
story fails if something goes wrong okay
if the object falls and now you have to
look at it again to pick it up yeah so
we will always do corrective Behavior
using Vision but most of the time we do
not need vision for performing an
action okay and this is going to be a
general principle in across the board it
is equally true in Walking it is equally
true in
manipulation
okay uh and I mean these are like the
details of uh of how it worked out for
this case so now I think I want to do a
demonstration for this class and I need
somebody to come up somebody who's like
a sports type person somebody who plays
uh football basketball whatever I need a
volunteer there must be some body in
this class who play some
sports so the people on Zoom you're
going to miss out on this experiment and
that's why you should come to class okay
you have to stand here okay now uh okay
so what what's your name Nema Nema okay
so Nea the experiment we're going to do
is similarly about what role does vision
play in Walking okay so Nema is standing
here and I'm going to give him a task
and here is this target it is some piece
of paper okay and I'm going to put it
down on the floor
okay your objective is to walk to this
piece of paper okay you guys can stand
up if you want to look and see what's
going on here there's trust me there's a
piece of paper here okay and what nema's
task is is to walk up to to to this
piece of paper and stop exactly at the
piece of paper
the challenge is that he has to do it uh
because if you could see it you could
keep keep running some feedback control
no I don't want you to do that I want
you to look at it think about it I'm
going to get out of the way okay there's
enough of a safety margin don't worry
you're not going to bang into the wall
and what you have to do is look at it
think about it and then just walk and
stop just stamp your foot down when you
think you hit exactly this part
and you you should not go ahead of this
you should not stop early you have to
stop exactly here and yes you have to do
it with the eyes closed okay okay so
release your hand just be natural yeah
but I think when I step on it I'll hear
it yeah at that point it's okay but then
you're no long no long that's the end of
the One 2
three okay so notice the error the error
is approximately 4 in and and he
traveled a distance of about 10 ft so he
traveled a distance of 10 ft do you know
how many steps you took five yeah okay
it took maybe five or six steps he
doesn't even know what they are you did
not plan that out in advance you he just
walked he walked about a distance of 10
ft and he had an error of about four or
5 in and now notice what the visual
system had to do the visual system had
to make a judgment of the
distance what did and and and make a
plan help make the plan then during the
execution when he was walking he was
walking blind what did the visual what
did the motor system have to do the
motor system had to do an integration
right it was counting the the steps were
going on there was some estimation of
okay this step might be 1.5 ft 1.6 ft
1.7 whatever it was I don't even know
what his steps were
those steps were being counted
integration of distance was happening
okay and then at some point the counter
said okay now you have traveled this
distance the brain doesn't even know
whether it
is what that absolute number is if I
asked you to judge what is the distance
and feet you probably will not be so
good but the motor system knew in the
currency that the motor system needs to
know which is in terms of uh you know
step walking steps thank you very much
okay okay so now you so this is of
course EXA exactly the same example most
of the time when we talk when we
walk uh we do it's also true when we
talk but
it gave all the right information for
executing this task so it takes a a long
time so it's a real pain I mean from a
compute Point of View Vision is a
nuisance right you have to do a lot of
work lot of computing has to be spent 30
to 40% of the brain is is spent on uh is
doing visual processing so there's a lot
of compute being used up but it delivers
something for you but your motor system
is smart enough that can actually take
care of all the rest from that there is
a there is a a sad case of somebody who
whose appropri system got uh essentially
destroyed because of some
illness and then uh you you should just
imagine that now his ability to act in
the world is gone he was able to recover
the ability to act but by using Vision
but and there there is a book that came
out on is called pride and the daily
Marathon the way he has to act is he's
always planning things out visually and
executing visually with vision feedback
and it can be done but it's really
really hard and really really painful
whereas for all of us who are lucky that
our proceptive systems are not are are
working we don't have this
problem
okay uh next uh so so let me summarize
this point here uh because the slide de
will be there with you so this
experiment was done by land in 99 and
then people have replicated this in many
different settings which is that the
eyes are directed where information that
will be useful in the near future is
likely to be found it's not the
information that you need right now that
you're just executing it's where the
information in the that will be useful
in the near future is well and then it's
similarly true while you're driving and
walking and so on in driving right I
mean this is in fact part if you once
you realize this point you will find
applications of it everywhere when
you're driving and you're taught you
learn driving where are you taught to
look you're Tau to look some distance
ahead right a few seconds into the
future when you're driving faster you
look further ahead so the unit of unit
is actually in seconds look 3 seconds
ahead 3 seconds could be a bigger
distance when you're driving faster and
a shorter distance when you're driving
slower but it's in in units of
time uh it's it's also true while you're
uh reading the score while playing music
and so on
okay next point the Gaze precedes and
guides movements of the arm or leg okay
I've already said this uh okay uh let me
now make the point that this is true so
this is for sequential tasks when there
are tasks which are not sequential in
nature uh but uh nevertheless eye
movements are necessary and there's a
very classic study here and this is uh
is shown in this uh in this uh slide so
this is a painting uh and this is the
some a Russian painting it's called an
unexpected visitor and the painter's
name is Ilia
Ren and uh there was a guy called yarbus
who was a Soviet scientist who studied
eye movements with some clever way of uh
measuring eye movement by putting
contact lenses to the eye so this is
like studies done in 1960s or 70s
something like that and it's like not an
experiment which is a very fun
experiment because you have to attach
something to your now they're much more
uh you know less intrusive ways of doing
the study and what he did was he said
look at this there's this painting and
now I'm going to give you a
task and then there'll be and then on
the while doing the task I will monitor
your ey movements but I'll give you
different
tasks so the first task is you give them
no task free examination so when people
are looking at this their eyes are
darting about so the points so what you
have are points corresponding to where
the eye fixates so the movement of the
eye is that the eye fixates at some
point stays there for a couple of 100
milliseconds and then there's a sard you
move to some other other point and then
you stay there for a little bit then you
s to another point so the ey is like
jumping around but there are these
discrete sort of resting points where
you stay for a few 100 millisecond then
you jump the eye jumps to some other
location so that's why you get these
points and then lines connecting them
okay so free
examination okay uh let's look at three
give the ages of the people what do you
think people are doing there what are
they looking
at faces because of face you have the
signal which enables you to judge
whether the person is young or old okay
uh remember the clothes worn by the
people okay that's five so clearly they
will look at the closes right uh there
is a a very subtle one uh estimate
material circumstances of the family so
is this family a rich family or a poor
family
so what enables you to judge that right
there are these paintings on the wall
there's a piano things like that right
the carpet I mean you're going to look
all around and from that you're going to
get a sense of are these rich people or
poor
people uh there's a really subtle one
which is a seven estimate how long the
visitor has been away from the family so
now you really have to look at the
emotional responses of people anyway
what's the highest level point high
level point is when we analyze an image
we do not do it
generically independent of what we are
what question we are going to
answer and now compare this to what goes
on in today's
blms okay what do we do we just we just
like divide it up into patches make
tokens you know shove that in right so
uh
now what does that mean the what it
means is that there's going to be some
basic knowledge which is captured and
which is good enough for answering
certain questions but if you want to
answer more subtle more difficult
questions then that
generic approach is probably
wrong right you want to be able to go
back and look in a active sort of a way
so the the perception process is an
active process you're just like in my
last lecture i t talked about touch
touches an active process you move your
hands and you get more information from
the sensor when you have a controlled
movement of the sensor well the same is
true for the I that you should think of
the I as an active
sens okay any question on
this okay next example so this is for
walking okay so this is uh uh like uh
you know now with this General Paradigm
now you can do experimental studies in
many different uh domains for many
different tasks so this is a paper uh
which is uh which is on walking and uh
let me show you the figure I think the
figure captures everything so so you
have uh these people walking around with
cameras on their heads but they're
walking in different kinds of terrains
right so there's flat terrain medium
terrain rough terrain I mean like an
extreme version of a rough terrain would
be you have to cross a river and there
are some Stone
across the river and you man you have to
manage to step across so what's your
guess of where where how far away you
look and how much do you look at the
ground depend in these different
settings yeah I would imagine in a very
rough terrain you have to look closer to
yourself yeah more attention yeah
exactly when I'm walking on absolutely
flat ground which is sort of boring and
well predictable then I just don't need
to look at the ground much right and and
this is exactly what they find how far
you look is related to the difficulty of
the terrain more difficult terrain you
look uh you look uh closer to you and
you also walk slower right I mean in a
way good way to think about it is it's
in units of Time how far away you look
is how many seconds you're going to uh
go okay uh and then I have like one
example here which I think I've shown
before and we'll which is we did all our
early work so so this work uh I mean the
all this philosophy of uh what vision is
used for was very influential for me it
tells me that basically most of the time
you should not be using Vision whenever
you try to solve a manipulation problem
or a Locomotion problem you should try
to see how much can you do using propri
reception propri reception should come
first and then you should bring in
vision for dealing with the more
difficult cases of the long range
planning so we had our walking robot and
initially our robot had no vision in it
okay uh and then we needed Vision
because we wanted to do this difficult
task so now it doesn't know in advance
where what the terrain is it has to plan
its footsteps carefully and this is
where trying to do it without wi would
be D
right
so so just keep this in mind when you
build walking systems you need to build
them such that most of the works because
blind people can walk you should have
the ability to walk without Vision but
if there is Vision then you can deal
with stairs you can deal with you know
stepping stones and so on and so forth
now this is uh this is from like now
practically two years old so this is a
the success story of our quadrupeds so
we could show that we could do this the
corresponding version of this problem
for humanoids is not solved we do not
yet have a robotic system that would use
computer vision or I mean some form of
vision this could be RGB rgbd Vision
which could walk in difficult terrain
like stairs Stepping Stones nobody can
do this today
okay so this problem the counterpart of
this problem for bips or humanid has not
been
solved okay so because part of the
purpose of this class is to tell you
what research problems are very open and
and the counterpart of this for like we
can't do this for one of our humanoid of
work
yeah yeah I mean the two-legged
Locomotion is harder than four-legged
Locomotion so that's the But but so
you'll have to it's a harder problem so
you will need you will need perception
in more settings and it'll be a more
challenging
problem
so so perception enables precise
Locomotion that's the model okay now
I'll uh let me get to talking about
prediction in Gold directed action so
let's uh let let me see if the next
slide I think has this so basically so
so good setting here is you're running
to catch this rabbit should you go with
the rabbit is now no you should go where
the rabbit will be right I mean and this
is true in in whenever you're playing
any sports right in soccer you don't run
to where the ball is now you run to
where the ball will be
right so you need uh so you need
strategies now exactly doing this uh for
various robotic tasks is is a challenge
it's not it's not like this is like a
solv problem people can't do this
readily but it's clearly the problem
that needs to be solved which is
anticipation and predictive
planning
right so uh so so I think i' I've stated
some of the principles here which is
which which are from this paper so uh
prediction allows humans to prepare for
the future
interactions and then uh you need to
know when and where an event is likely
to occur okay and then you plan
movements of the body so the body the
hands and the eye all of these are being
being done so when people say whole body
controled for humanoids it's turned out
to just mean referring to the fact that
okay the body doesn't fall down and so
on and so forth but in fact whole body
control should also mean thinking about
how the head moves how the eyes move and
so on uh are many of our current day
robotic systems we do not have movement
of the eyes we just have a fixed
camera and uh because this keeps life
simpler but I think the future is that
you attach a few Motors and you allow
yourself to move your move your head
because then you you automatically
increase the field of view because
otherwise you're struck with the field
of view of whatever your camera is which
for is often small like 30° humans have
a much larger field of view well we and
we are able to move our head and we are
able to move the eyes so my belief is
that as we get to these more complex
settings like humanoids we will want to
have control of the body the eye the
head the
eyes yeah
sure yeah was I mean that and some
people will do that but I think uh the I
think it can all be done with cameras so
why not so I I I I don't want to go into
this debate which has gone on in the
self driving car literature which is
should one do it all with vision should
one do it with liar and in the beginning
the algorithms which worked just on
Vision they were not very good so laa is
what you relied on substantially but as
the algorithms which are based on Vision
have become better I think less and less
the about the need for a Lia because if
you have multiple cameras like two
cameras you can get the stereo part
anyway liar maps are very sparse usually
right uh because of the way the sampling
Works they as pass and you always need
Vision because you want to read traffic
signs you want to read the uh you know
the street signs etc etc and uh I mean
it is possible to do it so I'm in the in
the camp which says do it all with
vision though I'm this is more a
question of taste rather than like a
fundamental point that oh it cannot be
done without like I mean if you like C
I'll use it I mean I don't care
right uh okay I made this point already
okay uh here are are uh this is like a
very dense slide because I just did some
cut and paste but I want to talk about
the problem because it's quite cool it's
a problem with past Sports so uh so
these this example is for Cricket which
people like me have played but not
everybody in this room has played but
you might have played baseball which is
similar or badminton or table tennis all
of these Sports have the same these all
of these have the same characteristic
which is that you there is the other
there's maybe a bowler or the the tennis
player on the other side is going to hit
the ball and you have to react to it and
what's the problem the problem is that
the ball is going to get to you very
fast and vision is so damn
slow so how do you how do you do this
how is the how do we cope how do we use
Vision to guide action
when when the when the the ball moves
fast I mean you can do these
calculations so in cricket the the
bowler uh bowls and the the ball bounces
on the ground and then it comes up and
then the batsman has to hit the ball and
and you have to do this within a few 100
milliseconds and the the the visual
system has a delay of 200 milliseconds
so it looks like you're in trouble so
that so so this so people have studied
this and they've found similar thing
applies in table tennis right so the
person's going to hit the ball it's
going to bounce and if you you think
that you will uh you will move your eye
to and you that you will track the ball
etc etc
well the 200 Mond delay will kill
you so what good the good batsman or
good table tennis players or good tennis
players do is they they operate with
very good predictive models so
essentially at the moment that the
bowler releases the ball okay or in
pingpong somebody hits the ball in the
first instance they have a very good
predictive model of where it's like to
land so they instantly make a sard to
where the ball is likely to land to to
hit the table or the ground in the cas
of
cricket and it and from that they will
extract that extra signal so the signal
is coming from uh I mean your eye has to
move right because there are different
locations so and for humans you have a
phobia and you need to the eye has to go
to different places to extract most
information so what you do is initially
you you try to extract information from
the other players hands and action
because that is based on your previous
experience playing ticket baseball table
tennis you have a sense of uh you know
like how the ball is going to be
released or like if you take the
baseball example the pitcher the way the
way he uh you know stands or what he's
going to do with his body or how he
moves his hand uh hand I mean all of
that is a signal for you which you have
which you have learned over time playing
the sport okay and then you you do
another uh sort of uh sampling based on
when the ball hits the ground which is
true in some settings but not others
yeah so so and then they have done this
study which is that the the better
players are actually better perceivers
so they have better systems for uh in
terms of how to track Mo move the eyes
to the right
location okay so that's the point here
so I think uh uh expertise in sports May
partly consist of being better at
anticipating whereas no noice baseball
batters are unable to track the fastest
balls Elite batters rely on a
combination of I head rotations to track
a fast ball so I have references here
and if you want there are psychologists
who have had enough fun uh studying
people playing all these Sports and get
a so so this is no longer a mystery so
like 20 years ago this was a mystery as
to how can given that vision is so slow
and these actions are so fast how can we
do it but now we have a sense of what's
going on
here
yeah some kind
of so for example in I would argue that
you know players
do anticipate to some extent but also
once the ball gets near to
body maybe
they
motion so
that can't be donee I disagree because I
because I know that there is this 200
millisecond delay how fast when the ball
moves how much does it move in 20 100
milliseconds so what you have this
illusion that you you're actually doing
this but this is an illusion it's no you
get some so just think back to when you
actually get new information is 200
milliseconds before you actually act
okay and that puts a constraint so it's
not the last part is not where you are
being driven by Vision Vision gave you
some signal at the time that the ball
hit the table and and you have enough
prior experience that you have models
which tell you where the ball is likely
to be and then you activate your Action
System you're not tuning it in the last
100 milliseconds you just can't your
your your process is too
slow it's not it's not fully true but
but but there's a the the fastest visual
pathway is like the vular ocular reflex
which is like for eye movement but even
that is like 50 milliseconds so it
varies a bit but 150 milliseconds is a
good uh is a good good number and there
is there is some subtlety I I
acknowledge that because uh the visual
information is used in multiple
Pathways uh but but uh still it is
slow this is not true of proception
right that's much faster
okay okay uh I have 10 minutes good uh I
want to talk about something called the
inference copy I think this is this is a
very interesting idea which is important
and it's it's important in
robotics uh efference what is what do I
mean by efference okay there is a term
afferent with an A and
efferent with an E so these are two
terms okay they refer to ner nervous
signal signals and neural
signals afferent with an a refers to the
signals which go from The
receptors to the brain so starting from
like your your tactile sensing for
example your sing sensors in your
fingers and so forth or your they there
is signal from that which goes to
through nerves to the spinal cord and to
the brain so that's what we call the
afferent signals right that's easy
what's the inferent signal with the E
this is in the opposite direction so
this is going from the brain to towards
the muscles okay from the central
processor to the
periphery and the
inference copy is essentially kind of
like okay what did the brain command
what was the desired action okay now let
me give an illustration of this so there
there's this example here of you when
you watch uh suppose a a train is going
by and now you you can either keep your
eye fixed and then the train is moving
or you can move your eyes to track we
can do smooth tracking so if you do
smooth tracking then what's happening on
your retina on a retina the train is
stabilized right so if you I just look
at the video corresponding to the train
it's like a stationary
train so if I have access to only that
signal you might say oh the the train is
stationary it's not
moving but the brain is not going to be
fooled by this right because the brain
knows that okay I commanded the eye to
move and the eye was moving at so many
degrees per second and then the train
was spe was stabilized so therefore it
must be the case that the train is
moving and if my eye was moving at 30°
per second and the train was stabilized
that means the train was moving at 30°
per second because your brain commanded
that movement of the
ice the inference copy is that command
turned from the
brain to move at uh 30° per second or
whatever was needed to track the object
so therefore this signal is available
for use and processing which is what was
the desired action so if I think of it
in terms of Robotics and then it's like
the sequence of controls right your so
there are the actual joint
angles which will be measured by the
afference the a for with a a and then
there is what did you desire what did
you want to be there's in the old
fashion literature they call this effort
of the will okay it's it's a very fancy
kind of
term to me this is very you know deep
sounding for just like the sequence of
Action commands but that's what they
used to use okay and and uh okay does
that make sense so and there's a
specific quote here this F Holst and M
start who propos that whenever a motor
command is sent to the muscles that move
the eyes or move the hands or whatever a
copy of the aend signal is
simultaneously sent to the visual areas
of the brain so then they can
essentially uh do the appropriate
transformation for
that okay and there is a fun consequence
of this which is that this is the reason
why you cannot tickle
yourselves okay so you know you if
somebody tickles you you laugh right
okay but try tickling I'm not going to
make the class go through a demo where
everybody tries to tickle the person and
then right I won't do that but uh try it
in the comfort of your own home okay and
then what you should what but what you
can try now is try tickling yourself to
see whether it makes you laugh
try it I I want to take a
photo okay and and you'll find you can't
do it and the explanation for that in
terms of this inference copy is that uh
it's a surprise when somebody else
tickles you but there's no surprise when
you you tickle yourself so therefore the
inference copy already has generated the
prediction of the consequences of that
and essentially you null that out right
because you it's a it's a expected
transformation you null that out so
therefore there's no signal left for you
to
get tickled with so this is
cool okay huh
huh
yeah no because there is an external
cause of that itch right so there's an
external signal which is why the itch is
really due to some
receptors uh on the skin so if if you
are itching it's because those receptors
are being activated so there is an
efferent there's an efferent signal
independent of what you choose to do
with your with your uh uh with your
brain I mean from your brain you will
plan to you know to itch that area but
the the itchiness arose because of some
response from the from the mechano
receptors actually the ones I talked
about last last week
yeah whereas when I decide to tickle
myself everything is generated by my
brain the desire to to take a generated
by brain there is no
external uh signal that's
responsible uh so uh so now I want to uh
jump to this quote which I like a lot
which is uh because uh predictive
modeling is what what is being suggested
here and there's the example of of table
tennis I think in the example of walking
uh running to catch a moving ball all of
these examples require predictive
modeling you need okay so how do we do
that so predictive modeling requires
essentially that we have
models and the person who listed this
idea way back was someone called Kenneth
K and I'll let you read the quote which
says if the organism carries a small
scale model of external reality and of
its own possible actions it's able to
try out various Alternatives conclude uh
which is the best of them react to
Future situation before their
eyes okay I think this is this is
written in English but if you want to
put this in math this is what the
control people have done right so X do
equals ax + b u i this and then we have
y = CX + b u
this refers to the observation part but
this is the evolution of the state right
so you have X is the state Vector U is
the uh the ve Vector of actions and a
and b are matrices so this is a linear
model if you want a more General model
you'll say x doal f ofx comma U where f
is some nonlinear function now control
theorists assume that they have access
to this function this is the model and
then that's how then they decide on the
optimal sequence of controls you to
achieve some goal which can be some kind
of a cost function subject to some
constraints so that philosophical idea
is is correct I mean I think the details
are obviously challenging and need to be
figured out in different settings okay
and uh so today this idea is uh is like
I I regard this uh now it's become a
buzzword so now I dislike it which is
the concept of a world model
so I mean I was saying these things like
seven eight years ago uh in various AI
settings so World models are to be
distinguished from word
models so a word model is basically what
your gpt3 is right it's predicting the
next word okay and the I mean it's a
model of language which is good which is
important because language captures so
much of the human experience but
language is merely a projection of
what's happening in the world I would
rather know what's happening in the
world okay and and model the world in
terms of these dynamical models which
are some kind of a generalization of the
kinds of models that people in control
theory have had and we need models like
that for the behavior of objects the
behavior of of Agents behavior of groups
of agents and so on and so forth right
and
that's I mean that's the way to achieve
AI so I I I want to make that it's it's
necessary for robotics it's necessary
for for uh for AI what is debatable is
how explicitly you need the models or do
you need the do you need to be able to
just have the optimal policies without
necessarily inferring the model in in
you know which I people in reinforcement
learning have talked a lot about that
and I don't have much to add
there so from this I have my slogan
which is common sense is not just facts
it's a collection of models so real so
when you are growing up what you are
doing is you building lots of models and
this is going to be the subject of the
next lecture which is uh intelligence as
you are growing up uh but what a child
is doing is essentially building up a
collection of
models uh so these are all aspects of
that which is uh we can predict sensory
changes in the world we can predict the
consequences of one's actions we can
combine predictions of various kinds of
movements I mean these are all flavors
of the same big
idea and I want to conclude with this uh
this last slide because this sets me up
for the next lecture which is uh I mean
say the theme of this lecture was vision
and action uh it's good to try to think
about how that ability comes about
because in robotics and AI we can try to
program it but for the human baby it has
to emerge over time with some genetic
component and then uh and the rest comes
from sort of learning and interacting
with the world and uh what the findings
are from the from the psychologist and
neuroscientists so in the case of vision
there are very clearly three stages of
development uh they like initially the
child is only able to respond to motion
signals so movement signals are probably
just like they genetically and then the
next to come are binocular stereo
disparity signals about four months of
age the child is able to get stereo
disparity and then uh more like five to
seven months of age is when static
pictorial cues like the signal from a
single image is available to have uh for
depth so effectively there are signals
initially available which are used to
train other signals which I used to
train then once you have that then some
new signal can be trained on top of that
so it's a it's a beautiful system and uh
we'll talk about it in the next hour but
now you have a 10-minute break